<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Mako info on</title><link>https://ramellose.github.io/mako_docs/examples/</link><description>Recent content in Mako info on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 08:48:23 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ramellose.github.io/mako_docs/examples/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Overview</title><link>https://ramellose.github.io/mako_docs/examples/intro/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 May 2021 14:38:09 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://ramellose.github.io/mako_docs/examples/intro/</guid><description>The mako software can be used to integrate multiple sources of data and write them to Neo4j databases, according to a pre-defined database schema. The case studies below have been selected to demonstrate the simplicity and speed with which mako is able to process microbiome data. In brief, the case studies address the following topics:
Rapid meta-analysis of multiple sponge-specific networks
Creating and querying hierarchical metabolic data
Validating an association network using microbe-metabolite interactions mined from literature
Working with a curated data set containing 60 unique studies
Querying 3- and 4-node cliques
Identifying associations linked to a metabolic pathway</description></item><item><title>HMA-LMA status</title><link>https://ramellose.github.io/mako_docs/examples/sponges/intro/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 May 2021 10:47:15 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://ramellose.github.io/mako_docs/examples/sponges/intro/</guid><description>Marine sponges, also known as Porifera, are a highly diverse clade of animals known for their ability to host complex microbial communities. Generally, these sponges can be categorized as either high microbial abundance (HMA) or low microbial abundance (LMA), depending on the density of the microbial communities they harbour (Gloeckner et al., 2014). Relatively little is known about these communities, since most members are uncultivated.
In this case study, we are going to integrate association networks derived from different sponge orders with a list of taxa previously found to be related to the HMA-LMA dichotomy.</description></item><item><title>Sponge networks</title><link>https://ramellose.github.io/mako_docs/examples/sponges/setup/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 May 2021 10:49:39 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://ramellose.github.io/mako_docs/examples/sponges/setup/</guid><description>For this section of the case study, we will interact with a running Neo4j database. If you do not have such a database available, please take a look at the Neo4j section of this web page to learn how to set up one locally or via Docker.
To upload our data, we need to open a terminal and navigate to the folder where we stored the files from the previous section.</description></item><item><title>Finding HMA-LMA subgraphs</title><link>https://ramellose.github.io/mako_docs/examples/sponges/queries/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 May 2021 10:49:49 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://ramellose.github.io/mako_docs/examples/sponges/queries/</guid><description>Find all Python code used on this page here: sponge_queries.py
With all networks and the HMA-LMA links available via the Neo4j database, we can start considering associations that could be linked to HMA-LMA status. For example, we might try to recover all associations between taxa that are both associated to HMA status in some way, with the query below:
MATCH p=(:Type {name: 'HMA'})--()--(:Taxon)--(:Edge)--(:Taxon)--()--(:Type {name: 'HMA'}) RETURN p LIMIT 25
This query first matches the HMA node and then passes through either a Class or Phylum node to connect to an association, which should similarly be connected to the HMA node.</description></item><item><title>Inflammatory bowel disease</title><link>https://ramellose.github.io/mako_docs/examples/ibd/intro/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 May 2021 09:37:05 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://ramellose.github.io/mako_docs/examples/ibd/intro/</guid><description>Inflammatory bowel disease (IBD) encompasses multiple chronic inflammatory conditions that affect the gastrointestinal tract. Although the prevalence of this disease is increasing worldwide, it occurs most frequently in North America and Europe, with approximately 0.3% of the European population being affected (Burisch et al., 2013). Over the past decade, the gut microbiome has been found to be implicated in disease etiology (Huttenhower et al., 2014). Yet, the numerous factors that appear to play a role in IBD make this disease challenging to study.</description></item><item><title>Microbe-metabolite links</title><link>https://ramellose.github.io/mako_docs/examples/ibd/associations/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 May 2021 11:31:44 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://ramellose.github.io/mako_docs/examples/ibd/associations/</guid><description>Before we can upload any data to Neo4j, we first need to create the appropriate files to upload. Specifically, we need the following files: tab-delimited taxon abundance and lineage files, and an edge list that links microbes to metabolites. We will use the R package phyloseq to generate the first file and use Hmisc to generate the correlations.
In an R environment, let&amp;rsquo;s first load the necessary packages and files. Make sure your working directory is set to the location where you downloaded the files.</description></item><item><title>Populating the database</title><link>https://ramellose.github.io/mako_docs/examples/ibd/setup/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 May 2021 09:37:13 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://ramellose.github.io/mako_docs/examples/ibd/setup/</guid><description>For this section of the case study, we will interact with a running Neo4j database. If you do not have such a database available, please take a look at the Neo4j section of this web page to learn how to set up one locally or via Docker.
To upload our data, we need to open a terminal and navigate to the folder where we stored the files from the previous section.</description></item><item><title>Querying IBD data</title><link>https://ramellose.github.io/mako_docs/examples/ibd/data/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 May 2021 09:38:21 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://ramellose.github.io/mako_docs/examples/ibd/data/</guid><description>Find all Python code used on this page here: ibd_data.py
Now that we have uploaded all our data to a Neo4j database, it becomes rather straightforward to identify taxa with the most associations to certain metabolites or specific classes of chemicals. Keep in mind that only the metadata for metabolite clusters in our correlation file were uploaded; therefore, some clusters and their related metadata are not currently included. Regardless, we can take a closer look at some metabolites that Franzosa et al.</description></item><item><title>A literature-curated network</title><link>https://ramellose.github.io/mako_docs/examples/metalit/intro/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 May 2021 09:38:46 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://ramellose.github.io/mako_docs/examples/metalit/intro/</guid><description>Many interactions between microbes are mediated through metabolites. Microbes can secrete metabolites like lactate, which can then be used by others as a carbon source. However, with only metabarcoding data, it is impossible to see metabolite fluxes or expression of genes that are required to facilitate such fluxes.
In this case study, we are going to import a literature-curated network of metabolite-driven microbial interactions. We will use this network to find associations in a different association network that could possibly be driven by specific metabolic interactions.</description></item><item><title>Association network</title><link>https://ramellose.github.io/mako_docs/examples/metalit/corrs/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 May 2021 09:39:25 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://ramellose.github.io/mako_docs/examples/metalit/corrs/</guid><description>For the remainder of this case study, we will interact with a running Neo4j database. If you do not have such a database available, please take a look at the Neo4j section of this web page to learn how to set up one locally or via Docker.
To upload our association network, we need to open a terminal and navigate to the folder where we stored the files from the previous section.</description></item></channel></rss>