<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Mako info on</title><link>https://ramellose.github.io/mako_docs/demo/</link><description>Recent content in Mako info on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 08:48:23 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ramellose.github.io/mako_docs/demo/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Working with Python scripts</title><link>https://ramellose.github.io/mako_docs/demo/query/intro/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Apr 2021 13:57:14 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://ramellose.github.io/mako_docs/demo/query/intro/</guid><description>When developing custom databases, it may be helpful to run custom queries as well, and to process these queries through Python scripts. In this guide, we will use five studies that we downloaded from Qiita to show how the mako API can be used in Python scripts. All code will be either Python or Cypher, meaning it can be helpful to run it from an integrated development environment (IDE) so you can run the scripts step-by-step from the Python interpreter.</description></item><item><title>Paine's food web</title><link>https://ramellose.github.io/mako_docs/demo/pisaster/intro/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Apr 2021 09:53:41 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://ramellose.github.io/mako_docs/demo/pisaster/intro/</guid><description>Neo4j is a native graph database, meaning it can store biological data in a way that is more intuitive to people unfamiliar with SQL. In this guide, we will use Paine&amp;rsquo;s food web (Paine, 1966) to demonstrate how database schemas work and how you can use Cypher queries to access a Neo4j database. We will use the Neo4j Browser to visualize query outcomes. All code in this guide will be in pure Cypher, meaning you can run it from the browser interface.</description></item><item><title>Demo data</title><link>https://ramellose.github.io/mako_docs/demo/vignette/intro/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Apr 2021 11:52:57 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://ramellose.github.io/mako_docs/demo/vignette/intro/</guid><description>In this vignette, several of mako&amp;rsquo;s functions will briefly be introduced with an example data set consisting of only 5 taxa and 20 samples. This data set is simple enough that most relevant nodes can be visualized in Neo4j Browser, making it feasible to follow along with all of mako&amp;rsquo;s operations.
The tables below give an overview of the data contained in the BIOM file. The file and associated networks can be downloaded from the mako Github repository.</description></item><item><title>Setting up the database</title><link>https://ramellose.github.io/mako_docs/demo/query/setup/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Apr 2021 13:57:31 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://ramellose.github.io/mako_docs/demo/query/setup/</guid><description>Before we can write any queries, the database needs to be populated first. We will use the BIOM and graphml files from the Code Ocean capsule here. You can replace these with any other BIOM or graphml file of your choice, like the demo data in the vignette.
First, we load all software packages and collect all the file paths of the files we want to write to the database.</description></item><item><title>Predator-prey interactions</title><link>https://ramellose.github.io/mako_docs/demo/pisaster/pisaster/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Apr 2021 09:53:52 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://ramellose.github.io/mako_docs/demo/pisaster/pisaster/</guid><description>Paine studied food webs of rocky shores in North America. In particular, he was interested in predator-prey interactions and carried out removal experiments to assess how species removal affected community structure. One species in particular appeared to have an outsized effect on the community - Pisaster ochraceus, a carnivorous starfish. In the subweb containing Pisaster and its food items, the numbers represent the fraction of food items in terms of number of food items and in terms of consumed calories (Figure 1).</description></item><item><title>Set up database</title><link>https://ramellose.github.io/mako_docs/demo/vignette/access/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Apr 2021 11:52:52 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://ramellose.github.io/mako_docs/demo/vignette/access/</guid><description>👉
The rest of this vignette assumes that you have a running instance of Neo4j to work with.
Please check out the instructions on how to start a Neo4j database, if you do not have one available yet. There needs to be an online database for mako to access before any of the following commands will work. The software will connect to the running database and interact with this.</description></item><item><title>Writing custom uq</title><link>https://ramellose.github.io/mako_docs/demo/query/custom/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Apr 2021 13:57:41 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://ramellose.github.io/mako_docs/demo/query/custom/</guid><description>All of mako&amp;rsquo;s driver classes are able to use the functions that call custom queries, so there is no need to close and recreate the driver to use these functions; however, for the sake of simplicity, the code below calls the ParentDriver class.
First, we need to start up the driver and connect to the database.
from mako.scripts.utils import ParentDriver
driver = ParentDriver(uri='neo4j://localhost:7688',
user='neo4j',
password='test',
filepath=filepath,
encrypted=False)
The ParentDriver only has three class methods: close, query and write.</description></item><item><title>Food web schemas</title><link>https://ramellose.github.io/mako_docs/demo/pisaster/schemas/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Apr 2021 09:54:03 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://ramellose.github.io/mako_docs/demo/pisaster/schemas/</guid><description>Neo4j does not enforce constraints, it is possible to store information in any way possible. The Neo4j introduction to graph database concepts provides some details on how this happens. To facilitate straightforward methods to access information, it can be helpful to come up with a set of rules for how data should be stored. By storing data according to a set of rules, it becomes easier to define general Cypher queries that can access the appropriate data.</description></item><item><title>Uploading BIOM file</title><link>https://ramellose.github.io/mako_docs/demo/vignette/biom/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Apr 2021 11:52:26 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://ramellose.github.io/mako_docs/demo/vignette/biom/</guid><description>Navigate to the location where you downloaded the BIOM file. By storing the config file, we can save ourselves the hassle of typing access information each time. For -fp, fill in the file path where the downloaded BIOM file is stored.
mako neo4biom -fp local_filepath -cf -u neo4j -p test -a bolt://localhost:7688 -biom demo.biom
If you access the Neo4j Browser (http://localhost:7475/browser/) and run the following query, you should be able to access all the nodes connected to taxa:</description></item><item><title>Connect to Neo4j</title><link>https://ramellose.github.io/mako_docs/demo/pisaster/connect/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Apr 2021 09:54:25 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://ramellose.github.io/mako_docs/demo/pisaster/connect/</guid><description>We can use the Neo4j Docker container to run Neo4j without needing to deal with a complicated setup. For this demo, the following command was used to start the Docker container:
docker run --rm -d --publish=7475:7474 --publish=7688:7687 --name=neo4j --env NEO4J_AUTH=neo4j/test neo4j:latest
We can navigate to the Neo4j Browser via the specified port: http://localhost:7475/browser/. To connect to Neo4j, we then fill in the rest of the information specified in the command; note that NEO4J_AUTH contains the username and password for the Neo4j database in the Docker container (Fig 3).</description></item></channel></rss>