<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Mako info on</title><link>https://ramellose.github.io/mako_docs/cypher/</link><description>Recent content in Mako info on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 08:48:23 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ramellose.github.io/mako_docs/cypher/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Schemas for associations</title><link>https://ramellose.github.io/mako_docs/cypher/schema/intro/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Apr 2021 16:29:54 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://ramellose.github.io/mako_docs/cypher/schema/intro/</guid><description>Database schemas are blueprints that describe how data in a database is organized. By defining schemas, we are able to design queries that can access data stored according to those schemas. Hence, mako&amp;rsquo;s core component is a database schema constructed from several OWL terms. This database schema also defines constraints for the data and provides guidance on how data needs to be uploaded to become easily accessible. Most functionality of the API uses the schema to rapidly upload BIOM files, check edge weights or find associations between related species.</description></item><item><title>Introduction</title><link>https://ramellose.github.io/mako_docs/cypher/introduction/intro/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Apr 2021 09:55:12 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://ramellose.github.io/mako_docs/cypher/introduction/intro/</guid><description>Neo4j databases can be accessed through Cypher queries. The range of possibilities with the Cypher query language is huge and this manual is not intended to be an exhaustive reference; rather, we will explain how data schemas help write Cypher queries, what the data schema used by mako looks like and show several queries that can be used to query a database generated by mako.
For a quick introduction on Cypher syntax, please take a look at Neo4j&amp;rsquo;s Introduction to Cypher.</description></item><item><title>Database schema for mako</title><link>https://ramellose.github.io/mako_docs/cypher/schema/overview/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Apr 2021 16:29:49 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://ramellose.github.io/mako_docs/cypher/schema/overview/</guid><description>The database schema used by mako was designed to meet several demands:
Simple querying of BIOM data
Simple querying of network data
Respect hierarchical structure of taxonomic tree
Straightforward access of networks for meta-analyses
Flexible inclusion of metadata
As a result, each of the items always present in networks and BIOM files have their own node label and can more easily be accessed. In contrast, property nodes are more flexible and can be connected to any other node.</description></item><item><title>Default nodes and relationships</title><link>https://ramellose.github.io/mako_docs/cypher/schema/default/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Apr 2021 16:29:43 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://ramellose.github.io/mako_docs/cypher/schema/default/</guid><description>Many of the nodes and relationships have properties that represent specific characteristics. The overview below contains a description of each node or relationship, its ontology term and any properties that the item has if default import functions are used.
Edge - NCIT:C75923
The Edge node is one of the most important nodes of mako and supports most of its functionality. While it is possible to connect Taxon nodes directly, the Edge node can be connected separately to Network nodes or Property nodes, so that more complicated Edge metadata is possible.</description></item></channel></rss>